[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast Landon it's such a pleasure to
meet you uh you know in in Zoom person
and uh I just right off the bat I just
really want to thank you for your time
and and thank you for for willing to to
talk to me and kind of like share some
of your story and wisdom I think uh many
people will will be happy to hear from
you yeah thanks for having me it's a
pleasure to be here yeah um so you so
you checked out a little bit of the
podcast anyway so you can kind of get
the format um it's it's really just just
conversational we can let it flow and go
where it may um I I would love to you
know there's no wrong or right way to do
it but I would love to start with some
form of Bio you know if somebody has
never heard of you they haven't heard
any of your of your um work on YouTube
or Instagram or anything you post on
social media or SoundCloud um maybe like
just a an elevator pitch or a little bio
would be a great place to
start yeah um I started off
I'd say it's been maybe like two years
or so since I started making Chillstep
mixes and originally um I didn't have
any plans for it um in terms of social
media like how far it would go I really
just um was working through my own sort
of issues and problems that I had in my
own personal life and chill steps were
kind of an outlet for those problems and
you know I heard of ch mixes before
people were making these videos online
on YouTube and I was listening to um
these philosophical mixes and it was
mostly Alan Watts and there were other
teachers that I looked up to and and
really resonated with and I thought how
cool would that be to make mixes for
those
teachers and so initially I thought it
was just a cool idea and I I started to
explore that and the more I listen to
certain lectures like Romos specifically
is one of my favorite teachers the more
I I dove into his work I found that the
mixes I was making was kind of an
emotional outlet for me it was like
almost
therapeutic so I started doing these
mixes and I thought you know I'll post
them online and I'll just share it with
other people and I wasn't really sure
you know if anybody was going to
discover those mixes right away I hadn't
had many subscribers I think maybe only
like 50 at the time time and my
intention wasn't to share it with other
people to kind of get acknowledgement
but just to share the joy and I started
to notice the views just dramatically
changed it kind of felt like overnight
but it was like a progressive thing and
yeah it just sort of changed my life in
the sense of of finding my own purpose
finding my own Dharma and and things
that um I could do to not only share my
own sort of Joy but share what I've
learned with other people and it started
initially the chill step mixes and then
I think it kind of expanded and and went
more into
teaching and so yeah I just would say
that it started there with the chil
mixes and then over time I started to to
venture out and just do things that I
love and just share that with other
people online
yeah definitely yeah it was really cool
to because I found you through the chill
step mixes as well um I want to
say I think that maybe Gangi was one of
the first ones that I had listened to
from you and it was the first time I had
discovered or maybe I had heard of you
but that was the first time I had heard
of gangaji and you know sent me into
just a whirlwind of pleasure exploring
her lectures she she's got a lot of cool
stuff on YouTube but um yeah I I love
that um because because it sent me to
your social media too and I feel like
you're just like a wonderful follow on
Instagram I I think that um you've got
an artist Eye that's for sure um you're
definitely handy with the camera you you
post great photos and then there's
always a great caption that really like
sends
me it kind of sends me back into myself
and it's it definitely is very spiritual
like even your captions just kind of
what you're expressing about what you're
going through what you're thinking about
that day or kind of like you know maybe
something that you have learned and
you're working through in your own life
you just typing that out in your
captions is like Ah that's nice that's
nice I think there's a lot of uh a lot
of people probably resonate in in relate
I mean so so you've gotten quite a few
you know you can go on Soundcloud and
listen to these and and quite a few
people comment on those and like thank
you and and you've told me that um
people enjoy like going on Hikes
listening to these mixes and stuff like
has it been a lot of good feedback from
other
people yeah I would say that's that's
the
really important aspect of it that has
really influenced the way I share myself
online is the the feedback I receive and
so when I started posting initially it
was on YouTube and then with the
copyright issues I had to go over to
SoundCloud but even in the comments
section of the videos people would just
share and they would just be so
vulnerable about the ways that the
Chillstep affected them and some of them
would share like I I listen to this on
my walks on my hikes or when I'm doing
yoga and even meditation and it just
brings me you know such peace and and I
I listen to those stories in the
comments and you know I've had people
reach out to me like through email and
even ask me for my number to just talk
to me and and share with me how it's
affected them and
it's it's so great to hear those stories
because you don't really recognize that
the things that you put out there and
the things that you share with other
people have such an impact and to be
able to connect to those
stories often I I'll listen to my own
mixes and I'll start to really feel into
the mix itself and recognize how many
people have actually listen to that mix
and it often makes me emotional because
I realize the impact of the mix and how
far it's gone and and just recognize
that recognizing that can be an
emotional experience to see you know how
far it's gone yeah yeah I mean it
definitely Taps into like this this
little spring of Love of sorts I mean
because it's you know a lot of the
content of the spiritual lectures are
very you know you said you're influenced
by by ramas you know he's he teaches the
path of the heart as he would say or the
the path of love you know so it is this
um I don't know it's cool to kind of be
a you know an usher of sorts of of like
ah here's this great spiritual knowledge
like there's some some good stuff in
here like check it out with some dope
Tunes underneath it you know it's cool
to kind of pass that along to people I I
love
it yeah I found that the lectures
sometimes at least for me can be quite
dense and something I didn't recognize
is people enjoyed the Paw so when the
bass would drop people would be able to
go into contemplation about what they
just heard and I never really thought of
it that way but I recognized in some
sense that I related to that in a sense
and also found myself in that
contemplation when the music kind of
took took over and I really resonated
with with that um but when I first
started the mixes um just the
combination of the music with the talk
the way I interpreted that process is I
felt like the song had to be perfect in
the sense of it had to convey the
emotion that was being formulated in the
talk and if the music didn't feel right
I would go back and find another song
and I think that's what really set my
mixes apart from other people that were
maybe trying to do the same thing and
I've heard people make some incredible
mixes not to say that you know mine's
like the best but um it was the way I
went about my process I think that set
it apart from other things that people
were hearing online because of it it was
tapping into that emotional aspect of it
so the song really had to be perfect
like if I try to mix and it wasn't going
in a right direction I would pause it
and just wait for another day and and
try again and I found that a lot of the
mixes some of them well mostly all of
them that I have on online now they all
got me into that flow State there was no
pushing for the finalized product it was
all just complete flow and I realized
that that was you know one of the best
products is when you can get into that
flow State and there's no frustration
involved in the
process yeah yeah you can definitely
that's definitely a role of an artist is
tapping into your own kind of intuitive
knowing of if it feels forced then
you're not going the right way you know
like it has to feel kind of like this um
you know to use Alan Watts's term Divine
Play it has to feel like this fun smooth
like ah of course that pause goes there
ah there that one is you know it's uh
it's very
much I I'm pretty fascinated um you know
my friend Brent who was on the podcast
um he he had asked me a question that I
think that you know I kind of butchered
my answer but it but it made me think
more and I contemplated quite a bit
basically he was asking kind of what's
the relationship
between my own spirituality and and my
Artistry like what is the handholding
there and it's really like set me into
myself and really thinking about um you
know my my role as an artist and my like
how how Natural State I feel when I'm
creating when I'm making something when
I'm you know being a conduit of catching
something from the Muse and trying to
like paste it into a form that I can
share with other people you know it's uh
it's this it's this dance for sure um I
mean so so I want to guess pose the
question to you how do you see you know
your role as an artist and your own
personal spirituality like do you
see like like how do they hold hands for
you in in your personal life like these
two separate things seem so far apart
but again they're kind of the same in a
lot of ways
yeah I would say that at first they seem
quite separate and then the way they
merge together for me
is quite natural in the sense that it
makes sense to do because you love being
an artist and then you love the
spiritual path and it almost makes sense
to merge them together because it's just
two things that you really love and you
really
enjoy and you know going back to what we
were saying about how it you get into
that flow it reminds me that ramas said
something like this when you're playing
the role
and you're playing the role and it's
just kind of coming through you quite
naturally and you're not busy being in
that role as an artist or as a Creator
it's just that busness of creating and I
really feel when I'm able to get into
that flow um I really find that it they
merge quite well both the creativity and
the the spiritual aspect of it yeah yeah
I I I hear that CU it's like
um yeah like the spirituality is this
Natural State already but then being
able to express it
without without this yeah like T putting
on the hat of like I'm an artist who
shares about spirituality you know it's
more just like here's some things that
I'm expressing and here's how they can
naturally Ripple outwards you know I
love um I'm love that you mention Romos
Romos is one of my favorites as well I
feel like I spent so much time listening
to Romos um in people people who listen
to my podcast are probably sick of me
like referencing Romos but uh so be it
um but yeah he I I I was thinking of um
I don't know if you ever heard the
lecture where he talks about how he was
driving and he was just driving for a
long way and he had his uh was it Mala
or mandala and he's just repeating his
Mantra and he's in his head and he's
just like playing with his beads as he's
driving and then he gets pulled over and
um and there's this this moment he
describes it so nicely I I forget the
name of the lecture but uh it's he
basically is just like bringing out this
love in this police officer because he's
not treating him like a police officer
in a uniform you know it's just like
another being and I'm another being and
and here we are and like he was talking
Ron B was talking about how like the cop
almost didn't want to let him go at the
end cuz he's just like so in love with
each other just being of just being you
know two beings walking each other home
as he would say rather than like I'm
someone who needs to obey the law and
you're a police officer and you can get
me in trouble you know it's because we
get so caught up in seeing ourselves and
one another in our roles that we miss
who we really are right so there is this
beauty of like just allowing allowing to
be there and not trying to run to our
identity and not trying to like hide
behind our uniforms so to say you
know yeah yeah I find that merging the
two as a Creator and then as someone
who's also spiritual it really helps you
see the role in a new way it helps you
play the role and also detach from the
role because I think you said you know
we get we get lost in those roles and
without the emergence of the the
spiritual aspect of it you can kind of
get locked into your role as an artist
and you know this is who I am and this
is what I do and so I I that's why I
think it's quite natural to bring in
that element of spirituality to it to
help you detach from it as much as you
can yeah yeah very much so it's it's
really been a really cool thing for me
to com contemplate you know um it was
something that was you know I it was
obviously part of my thought process
thinking about my role as an artist in
my spirituality and how they hold hands
but uh certainly since since Brett
mentioned that to me I think it's been
more at the Forefront of my mind and and
uh you know how how to do both of those
things well because you know our
spirituality is so personal you know
it's so um as much as it's it's not
personal actually in so many other ways
it's it's very personal to like you
don't really have to share it you don't
have to have other people believing the
same things you do you don't have to
convince anybody of anything you know
it's all that but it's also um like this
very real experience that we can we can
certainly feel feel you know if we're
able to communicate it in some way or
like draw draw a picture of what we're
experiencing there's something within
other people that is that is spoken to
you know and I think that's like the the
core of art is really this how do you
take this very personal thing this thing
that seems very um you know you try to
express it in plain words to other
people and it almost sounds like icky
because it's so personal and like ah
it's your stuff you know you keep that
to yourself sort of thing but it's but
you know experiencing specific human
emotions and um you know it's it's we're
all very aware of of just being human
and and
how like difficult it can be and how
painful it can be and how beautiful it
can be and when we can find ways with
our art to kind of Pierce the Veil of
our identities and just speak to that
like hey you know as Romas would say
again like I I'm in here you're in there
how'd you get into that one you know
that
just that little essence of of just
being you
know yeah I think
appreciating the uniqueness of
everyone's Journey which feels quite
personal at times just appreciating that
unique perspective in someone else can
help you come back to that that
realization that you know this is
something we all share and through the
uniqueness of of your journey you know
with mine we can still see that it's a
shared experience but yeah I found that
uniqueness in everyone and and through
their own perspectives and and what they
share online and and teachers you know
of all kinds just sharing their journey
and you know really appreciating their
unique path really helps you see that
people go through this in different ways
and they take different Journeys you
know whether you're you're Buddhist or
or Hindu um just appreciating
those unique paths all leading to the
same
realization yeah it's quite a beautiful
thing to like the to poke at or you know
shine a light on the through line
between all of our experience you know
like however we put it into the words
however we try to like language a VI it
you know it's it's all uh we're all kind
of it's it's all the it's all the same
Moon that the hands are pointing at you
know so to say um man so I would love to
I would love to ask you about your
spiritual journey as far as like have
you always been into this sort of stuff
did you stumble upon lectures on YouTube
did you grow up with like a you know
Buddhist background up upbringing were
were you always spiritual like how did
you even kind of first stumble into any
of this sort of
stuff I would say it it started only
just a few years ago um around 2016 I
had my kind of Spiritual Awakening and I
wasn't spiritual before that um you know
my parents were religious in the sense
of one was Christian and the other one
was um into the Jehovah Witness which
was really interesting because those two
kind of conflicted with each other and I
didn't really know where I stood with
with religion or or spirituality and I
didn't know much about spirituality in
the sense of
there being something um outside of the
normal um religious perspective of there
being one God like one specific person
and it could be like spirituality seemed
something that was less personal it
wasn't just a person you kind of look up
to in the sky so I I I knew nothing
about that really and then when I had my
Spiritual Awakening I was really drawn
to Buddhism first and actually I I I got
into um Buddhism through through someone
online who was making spiritual videos
about his path in Buddhism and he
eventually went to Hinduism um I don't
know if you know him his name originally
was Ki
Fresco and his name now is
vadas oh oh okay maybe I I think so I
feel like that that rings a
bell does he have like a dark brown
beard he does he had had um he had uh
dreadlocks for a while yeah yeah yeah
okay yeah I'm I'm picturing who you're
talking about yeah yeah he was just you
know a normal guy in the United States
lived in California and he was sharing
Eastern philosophy
online and I originally I think was
drawn to exploring the philosophy after
I went through a heartbreak back in 2016
and I really felt like a victim in my
own mind and with the world and I kind
of just was really depressed at the time
and was really looking for something to
alleviate the pain and I went online and
was watching videos about spirituality
and it was interesting not in the
emotional aspect of it eventually I got
into it more in depth into spir
spirituality for that reason but I think
what kind of drawed me in initially was
um things like seeing auras and the
Paranormal stuff and I was always kind
of drawn into that but the more I kind
of went down that rabbit hole the more I
was um open to the emotional side of it
of having inner peace and alleviating
trauma and and all these different
things and so when I discovered badas he
was making these videos about Buddhism
and I had never heard anything about
Buddhism or or Hinduism or any Easter
philosophy and I really resonated with
it there was just something in me that
had that recogn recognition that this
was true for me in some way so I I
really dove into that um Buddhist rabbit
hole for a while and then I kind of took
on that label and I was like I'm a
Buddhist and uh you know over time I
watched him move from Buddhism to
Hinduism he would share videos about the
Sky ROM do and I I initially thought to
myself I don't know if I'll get into
this Hinduism path because he's talking
about this in a more devotional sense
and I don't really there was something
in me that had resistance to that um
because it reminded me of how my parents
viewed religion and I remember as a kid
just saying to myself I don't need
religion I don't need the Bible to be a
good person and I kind of felt like it
was something that people were depending
on to to live their lives in such a way
that was like quote unquote perfect and
um it was just something I had a lot of
resistance to so initially I resisted
Hinduism because of that devotional
aspect but then I kept seeing him
mention this person Rond do and I
thought I'll just listen I'll just give
it a shot you know and I listened to
rams's lectures and I found a resonance
in that and then I discovered his
journey with his Guru and and his path
in Hinduism from being you know a
psychologist at Harvard to going to
India and then traveling down this this
Hindu path I was like oh this is quite
interesting I I kind of also took that
that leap from Buddhism to him
Hinduism and at first I I started to say
oh I'm Hindu now and I took on that
label as well and then the more I
learned in my journey the more I
recognized um what's really behind all
the labels and the trying to identify
oneself with a particular path and I
realized how so many religions
Christianity as well and some aspects of
it they all have that same truth to it
maybe describe in different ways um so I
really just kind of let go of all the
labels and I was like you know wherever
I can draw truth from um I'm just gonna
go with that and not really say like I'm
Hindu or I'm Buddhist you know so I
would just say I'm I'm on a spiritual
path I'm spiritual yeah I really like
that you just said wherever I can draw
truth from I think I think I've landed
in a very similar position W with my own
path like um yeah I'm not caught up with
trying to like figure out which one it
is that is for me you know which one can
I devote myself to fully and then I'll
like have it all figured out and that's
my identity from here on out you know
it's for me it's been kind of the same
thing is I keep just uncovering these
the like layers of cloaks that I can
take off like oh I don't need that one I
don't need that one you know just just
in in the pursuit of of Truth and it has
to like really feel
intuitively um in alignment with like
who I am or or or it feels like I'm
forcing it you know and it's um I think
I think a lot of people I think a lot of
people to resonate with your path man I
think um Wow since 2016
so it's interesting how many of
us kind of start the spiritual path from
trauma or heartbreak or like suffering
you know it's like I'm always asking
people you know like was it psychedelics
that led you there was it was it tragedy
um I think
um it's it's it's so cool
cuz like you you kind of get to this
this point where the person that you
have made or the person that you like
unknowingly are or have been just simply
doesn't work out for for you any longer
it just it's like it's almost like the
person breaks and you're there trying to
find some sort of grounding some sort of
like way to go for forward you know some
sort of um not even just new identity
but
like like you know all the answers that
you've heard from people around you or
your parents or your family or whoever
like you know you could try to just Jam
them into this you know the the old
Square Peg and a round hole thing it
just doesn't seem like anything fits and
then so we're kind of sent sent into our
own world of of really taking it serious
of man I've got to find something to
give me answers like I'm suffering I'm
I'm heartbroken you know I've got to
find something and then nowadays we have
like we're talking about last night like
the internet and social media and you
know just YouTube lectures like what an
incredible thing you know how many years
ago would it be that in order to get
this kind of spiritual knowledge you
would have to know the right person and
and really like travel travel somewhere
in the mountains the Tibetan mountains
and give the right person the path
password so you can go talk to the to
the enlightened master so to say and he
you know maybe he'll give you some
answers but now we can we can be like
walking on a path next to our house
listening to enlightened Masters in our
headphones and having profound
legitimate you know Spiritual Awakening
so it's I I I think a lot of people are
kind of set on that path um I was
telling you about um Brent um Brent
Spirit who who teaches a lot about
Kundalini um he he does like this Q&A
these these Zoom calls every week that
that have been really enjoyable I was
mentioned to you last night that um a
lot of people are like suddenly falling
onto this path of of Awakening and it's
so destabilizing you know and so to find
something that feels like home feels
like something we could hold on to a
little bit and kind of like it helps us
get to The Next Step At least you know
whether it's it's just a lecture or it's
like one of your Chillstep mixes or um I
mean I wonder how many people you've
introduced to Romos alone just from like
stumbling upon one of your mixes and
then they went down the whole be here
now Network like rabbit hole of of
wonderfulness you know yeah it's uh it's
cool man it's it's
cool like our paths how how how we
stumble into it it really is so
cool yeah definitely I like you said
going back to how you described the
person breaking that was just
so such a great image of how it worked
out for me because that's the place I
found myself in and I would say the the
breakup was just like the Tipping Point
for me it was like a an accumulation of
things I had gone through in childhood
and at that point it it felt like a
breaking down um kind of like a death of
the old way of doing things I knew
something had to change and so when I
stumbled into this one video in
particular particular before I found
radas it was just like the core of
spirituality I think that was the title
of the video and he mentioned like when
people have this spiritual
awakening oftentimes it can be quite
random but sometimes it's through
traumatic pain and I just remember
tuning into that part and I really fell
into that feeling of just being in such
a a low place and and wanting to have
this Awakening so again I fell into that
rabbit hole through this video and just
really realized
um how the old way of of doing things
and and looking for answers through my
parents and through this kind of
westernized version of religion just
wasn't
working yeah yeah and then
it's I mean I think so many people like
you know that that's something we hear
often often is kind of like the the
Western vers Eastern or um the Western
mind you know that took me a while to
kind of unwind well what do you mean
like so I think fundamentally different
as a Westerner than you know people who
have experienced these spiritual
teachings from from a young age um I
mean that's I've really fallen in love
with the person who could bridge the gap
between the Western philosophical
spiritual stuff in the Eastern you know
Alan Watson ROM dos super huge for me as
well um so I I wonder man what I always
like to do with the with the podcast is
like I always remember that not
everybody is so dipped in all of these
like spiritual terms or like even even
being open to the word spiritual I'm
sure you've experienced it you know just
like sharing your own interest with
people I can watch people shut down like
the second I say words like God or
spiritual you know of course it makes
sense but we have these preconceived
ideas of what that already means and
some of it is so there's such this quick
reaction for a lot of Western people
that the second we hear the word
spiritual we're like okay dude you know
it's like all right cool like I'm not
listening you know but um sometimes I
wish that I could like rename that word
and just you know like find some sort of
you know more welcoming sounding uh
mouth movement for someone to like
really get into it because it's it's not
something that's so far out there it's
it's really like a profound thing that
can um enhance and explain a lot of our
internal experience so I
wonder do you have interactions with
people who who you know are are not at
all spiritual um but like you're able to
maybe like introduce them to these
topics in in some sort of ways like how
do you how do you describe spirituality
to people who aren't immediately into
it actually um one of my best friends
he wasn't spiritual in this in the sense
like I was like he was interested in in
some things like astrology and knew like
a little bit of the basics but didn't
really um grasp the whole who are you
question and and I could sort of notice
that um but the more you
just um explain things in in quite a
different way without using words like
God and and whatnot you can sort of see
people take more interest in it and I
noticed I had some trouble um with this
myself because I found the word God was
Troublesome and when I got into Hinduism
the the word of God kind of created some
resistance in me and I think that's what
initially um kept me away from it and
then actually vadas posted a quote on
his Instagram that made me think about
it a little bit more
deeply something like uh if you have
trouble with the word God you have more
work to do and I just thought what does
he mean by that like what do I have to
work on and the more I started to just
be curious um and to be open to being
wrong um I just sort of delved into the
meaning of that word and and the
misconceptions that are around that word
and a lot of people I think they pull
back because of these misconceptions and
the way the word has been used over the
years
and Hinduism allowed me the freedom to
regain the power again of using that
word God and and reestablish it in a new
way by recognizing that it doesn't have
to be what I thought it was in the
western sense of of being Jesus Christ
you know some guy that is in the sky it
could be non-personal it could be an
energy that pervades the Universe and
you can use different words that make
you feel more comfortable you don't have
to use the word god um but initially
that quote that vadas posted it made me
want to figure out what my resistance to
that word was and and why I had the
resistance um but initially I used words
like Source universe and and things that
helped me feel more comfortable so I
would encourage people to do what feels
comfortable but always be open-minded to
to understand your resistance to certain
words and and really when I describe it
to to my best friend I I try and use
words that are comfortable for him and I
find that the more I do that the more
open e is and you can sort of see that
transformation in people when they
become a little bit interested in it and
then they find more things that um that
resonate with with them they start
seeking it out on their own time
yeah yeah I you described that so nicely
I I love that yeah and that does help to
use different these different words you
know because there's even certain
scenarios where words like Source or um
you know those can also be be a turnoff
for people so it is nice to kind of feel
out people's comfortability and kind of
um you know me I'm trying to trying to
like notice when I do say something you
know like oh oh I can see their body
language is kind of rejecting that thing
so like let me real back in and you know
I don't I don't need to shove my
terminology down their throat like I
think there's something that we could
both have a conversation about here that
um you know I don't need to be a slave
to my own interpretations and in you
know specific words about what I'm
talking about there's something within
both of us that I'm trying to point to
so whatever words I can add in or or
take away are uh you know helpful to
that ushering in of of of epiphany in in
a way um I I I want to go back a little
bit to um you you mentioned astrology
and and you mentioned um I think that
you've mentioned correct me if I'm wrong
do you do tarot readings tarot cards I
do yes yeah cool yeah so I'm um those
are those are you know I don't have a
ton of information I don't have a ton of
knowledge about either of those things
uh astrology or tarot but uh I I will
say I have some awesome friends who when
they describe when they kind of like
break apart those things for me or they
kind of describe the way they interpret
it or kind of how they do uh tarot
readings it it totally resonates I'm
like oh that's awesome that that totally
makes sense um so as much as my
knowledge is pretty sparse when it comes
to those sorts of things I'm really
fascinated by it um I wonder you know
what what have been your experiences
with like tarot readings or even
astrology like and even how did you get
into that stuff like like what what
sparks you with that stuff
too I think I initially found a lot of
my information um on YouTube and just
sort of had a curiosity for it but I
think that Curiosity was really um born
out of one of my experiences I had at a
spiritual convention they were having
tarot readings and I kind of just
decided to just get one that day and
just see what it was all about and uh
the guy that was doing the reading for
me he was really hitting on a lot of um
personal points in my life that I didn't
think he'd have information about
and it was so specific in the way that
it just took what I was going through
and kind of laid it in front of me and
really confirmed my experience and I
think that little bit of validation
helped me come to terms with what I was
dealing with and I think that's what
terot and and Oracle can do for people
is show them where they're at in the
present moment and I think a lot of
people have misconceptions about tarot
and um it being a a medium to tell the
future and while it can predict certain
possibilities based on the energetics of
the present moment it is more so about
where you are in the in the present
moment how you're dealing with it and
maybe some of the limited perspectives
or beliefs that you have right now that
are contributing to your situation so I
find that I use tarot for myself mostly
um I can do readings for other people
but I initially did it for myself to
have a better connection to what I would
call God or source and and to myself
really and so the tarot kind of just
helps me see where I'm at in the present
moment and how I could navigate my
situation with a little bit more
awareness yeah yeah absolutely it really
is kind of a a a gift of knowledge you
know know as much as it's definitely one
of those things that you know with
anything like not just wholeheartedly
believing 100% um or just like thinking
this has all the answers or like you
said you know like oh this can predict
my future you know and I think most most
tarot card readers are are really not
even trying to do that I feel like if
you just take a second to listen to them
like most of them are pretty straight up
and honest about you know like I'm not
this isn't 100% like here's I'm reading
these things and like take what
resonates that that sort of thing and um
yeah I found um I've actually never had
an in-person reading but I will say I'm
pretty intrigued by um you know via my
you know one of my vices and addictions
is mindlessly scrolling on Tik Tok uh so
it's kind of been fun to to kind of see
what different um you know like tarot
card readers pop up and like it's kind
of interesting to like you you know
again I think that it's like it's
playing with the algorithm and it's you
know it's watching what you're what
you're hovering your finger on that sort
of thing but I will say there's a little
bit of fun play of as I'm scrolling
through just to kind of like stop and go
huh I kind of like the way that sounds
you know it's it's I I think there's
it's there's a little danger in like you
know not like really wanting all that to
be true you know like oh this perfect
video found me you know but um I don't
know I find it fascinating you know I
think it's
fun yeah the with the tarot readings
online and on Tik Tok they're really
interesting
because sometimes you can feel that pull
to a certain reading because it's
hitting something in you that's that's
resonating with it and maybe the the
just of the whole reading isn't 100%
accurate but again if there's a little
bit of Truth in it why reject it and so
sometimes I'll take little bits of
videos that I find on the internet
but it's really important for people to
have discernment when a reading comes
across because a lot of people are doing
it for their own egoic reasons of making
money and and things like that and Tarot
is I think such a a sacred practice that
should be preserved in some way for
helping people in in a more genuine
sense and I think a lot of people when
they're posting you know these videos on
Tik Tok they can be do they can do such
a disservice in the way they perpetuate
someone's limiting beliefs so some of
the tarot readings you'll say like
you'll see oh your ex is gonna come back
and you know and people can really be
like oh my gosh she's coming back you
know and that can do them such a
disservice in the way they they cling to
something and you know while it may be
true um you have to just use your
discernment and see if the message is is
really keeping you in that um separate
space or that attached space and it's
really hard for people to have
discernment so you know I try not to
consume um tons of readings online I
have like specific readers that I'll
listen to and really that's just one
reader um on YouTube her name's uh
gemstone tarot she's an older lady she's
been doing tarot since she was 17 and
you can kind of tap into your own
discernment um by using your intuition
and and just really seeing if it feels
right for you but again if you don't
have that space in you that is is really
aware of your own um addictive
Tendencies or or your own attachments
it's really easy to um sort of cling to
these readings that you're coming across
online yeah yeah yeah I think yeah you
got to be kind of careful because you
can get made a sucker pretty quick you
know like you could you could be kind of
giving over your power in a way that you
didn't really need to be or um you know
I I've noticed in myself that's the same
thing as I try to discernment is
something you know I I learn firsthand
because it it was interesting to notice
I think when that when the tarot reading
stuff started first popping up on my
feed there was times where even without
really wanting to I was believing more
than more of it than I really L on like
found myself you know saying something
just for example that that you is like
oh your ex is coming back or something I
would have something similar and then I
would notice that I mean like 20 times
20 times the rest of the day I thought
about that thing that they mentioned
like oh this is coming your way and then
I kind of had to take a step back and go
like well man if I'm like I'm like
changing the way that I'm perceiving my
everyday life based off of this kind of
like random algorithmic Tik Tok video
that popped up you know I should be a
little more careful with my you know
it's kind of like lending the power of
my mind into into you know someone
else's whatever their reasoning is for
posting the video it's just you know
it's just kind of dangerous it's I think
using discernment and then uh I mean I'm
drawn to say even beginner's mind I
think it's a pretty big Buddhist term if
I recall is bringing The Beginner's mind
of
like
just I don't know be being open to to
what they're saying but I don't know I
guess just not believing it
wholeheartedly you know right yeah yeah
yeah that's a big part of it if you go
into it believing everything I could
imagine that a lot of the times you'll
be very disillusioned in your own life
just you know taking the word of of
someone on the
internet yeah yeah it's really it's
really giving it's giving your power
over and and you got to like it's it's a
balance you know I I think um you know
so many people who have these sudden
spiritual Awakenings or even just are on
a spiritual path even if it isn't so
dramatic and and sudden as it is for
other people um it's pretty easy to get
sucked into the abyss of the algorithm
whether it's Tik Tok or YouTube or or
whatever it is you know I think it's a I
mean when I first started getting into
it um I was so obsessed with just like
sometimes it would spit out such cool
videos on YouTube to me that I'm you
know staying up till 2: a.m. just like
contemplating the most just ESO
far-fetched things ever and it's fun but
you know as Ron BOS would say you've got
to you know remember always remember
your Buddha nature and your Social
Security number you know like like you
got to keep one foot in on the ground
with a lot of this stuff too
so I I I want I wanted to ask you um and
feel free to to not share if if you
would rather not but have psychedelics
played any role in your in your
Awakening or have you any experience
with that psychedelics
I have yeah um well I first started with
LSD and I will say that was a bit too
intense for me it lasted for I say more
than 12 hours and I remember taking it
late at night and then having to do
responsibilities in the morning and I
didn't sleep all
night so I had that experience and it
was just it was all visual stuff you
know I was just and all the the trippy
visuals and there
was not a single part of me that was
like contemplating philosophical things
so that was just kind of an intense
experience and then I thought to myself
I'm going to try mushrooms and so I've
done mushrooms um quite a few times I
would say at least four times um I
haven't used them in a really long time
it's been a long time since I've used
any kind of psychedelic um and those are
the only two sub substances that I've
ever tried and I had experiences with
and when I did mushrooms it was
definitely different than LSD it was it
was a little visual I had that um
breathing wall effect that people talk
about where you can see your walls
breathing and and all that but it really
brought me into my mind and I was
contemplating things like the ego and
and I had some
spiritual um basis before moving into
psychedelics so when I was using the
mushrooms I could contemplate these
Concepts these spiritual Concepts
because I had that um I familiarized
myself with some of those and when I was
drawn into I would say one of my most um
important experiences that I've had on
mushrooms um it started off being a
really great trip at first um I remember
just being being at total peace when it
first started I remember being in my
kitchen summer windows were open kids
were getting off the school bus and
there was just this slight breeze in the
air and I just remember sitting in the
kitchen at the table and just kind of
glancing out the window and and feeling
at complete peace and the only thing
that I could think of um was this phrase
everything makes sense and I don't know
how to describe that or anything I was
like thinking to myself like what what
makes sense you know I couldn't answer
that question but I just felt
like I knew I was at complete peace and
then it was interesting that that
totally began to change and the trip the
um the trip changed in such a way that
it turned into a bad trip and I came
down into my basement where I was living
I live with family and I came down into
the basement where I kind of reside and
there wasn't a lot of light in the
basement and I think that played into it
I was by myself during this whole
experience and I remember coming into
the basement and just falling into like
a depression and acknowledging my own
fears I didn't know I had and I think
that when I was researching mushro muss
there was a lot of um talk around how
mushrooms bring out some of your deepest
fears and so I was recognizing that
maybe I was having that experience of
just uncovering fears I didn't know I
had and I remember when I was in that
depression um during the trip the fear
that came up for me was feeling alone
and being
alone and I I really began to to panic
during the trip and I had to go online
and and look up ways to kind of reduce
the effects of the Psychedelic and I I
went on YouTube and I was listening to
this video and this sky was kind of like
talking you through it like reminding
you you're tripping right now and to
just to just breathe and relax I
remember listening to meditation music
kind of laying on the bed and just being
all curled up in this this really low
space and just wishing that the trip
would end and eventually
it kind of um like I got past the peak
of the experience of the trip and then I
started to come down a little bit and
started to feel more reassured of like
it's it's coming to an end now and I'm
returning back to my normal self and I
realized that that experience showed me
the possibilities of Awakening and of
the spiritual path and how one can you
know be at peace and and come to
enlighten M and and what it's
like go more deeper into my spiritual
path Lon you you just uh you paused for
a second will you just repeat that last
sentence there it just skipped out just
a
hair I would say that psychedelic
experience I had really helped Propel me
forward into my spiritual journey more
deeply because I recognize the potential
possibilities of the path yeah yeah nice
that's yeah beautifully said thanks for
sharing that too by the way I love to
hear um
uh what was the word that you were
thinking of at the beginning before it
got bad you were saying um like it's
it's all okay or something like that it
all makes sense it all makes sense yeah
I was I was giggling because um for me
when I do mushrooms uh for whatever
reason uh well I think it's because
because I've like listened to so much
romdas I I feel like I hear romos' um
gurus say um don't you see that it's all
perfect and so like my that is kind of
like a a mantra that happens for me if I
take any sort of mushrooms is I'll just
be like ah it's all perfect don't you
see it's all perfect and it kind of like
unwinds whatever I was I was trying to
hold on to um yeah I mean I I I love
that you Shar that too
because um you know as we're learning as
as more and more of like the Psychedelic
world is is being spoken about and being
worked into and like being you know
scientifically studied and helping
people with their mental health and like
being applied to certain you know
veterans and people with um you know
like
nonresponsive um major depressive
disorder all these incredible things um
one of one of the biggest things and it
seems like it's just this casual like oh
make sure you do this but one of the
biggest things that you'll hear is set
and setting you know like your your
environment
your how you've set up your day making
sure you have you know nothing super
important to do in a few hours making
sure the people around you are
understanding or um give you your space
like there's all these these things
about your set and setting to set up to
give you like the most optimal um
experience but
also also learning and finding ways for
us to express as a culture that a bad
trip isn't necessarily just that you
know on the other side of it there's
there's something to be taken from that
um that you know is is turbulent as the
experience can be while you're while
you're undergoing it like all you want
to do is stop it and like how do I stop
tripping out and I'm having a bad trip
you know it's I'm glad you found that
video that seems to be kind of helpful
you know even just like reminding us to
breathe and like oh dude you're you're
tripping so it's okay just you know
you're going to be fine that sort of
thing is very helpful but um I think um
you know that that integration
afterwards is I think you'll hear many
people talk
about
psychedelics it's not just the trip that
you're benefiting from it's like I mean
sometimes there's like the following
weeks and the following months even
you're these things that you kind of
Unearthed within you are are now kind of
being worked out and they're kind of you
know they might have been on the
peripheral side of your vision of
yourself but they're kind of working
their way in in front of you for for you
to deal with um I did um
and I still am not 100% sure where I
land with it I'm hoping that hoping that
I can continue to learn with it but I
did micro dosing of siloc cybin for like
five months um a couple years back and
um it it was interesting like the things
like all of my preconceived ideas of why
I was micro doing like okay well I'm
dealing with major depressive disorder
and I'm not going to do I'm not going to
do anti-depressants ever again so like
let's try maybe this will help with
these things and blah blah blah all
these like things about me that I
thought I needed to fix I thought that
those were going to come up when I was
micro doing but instead one of the
weirdest things I've talked about it
before is I actually started accepting
my like more like aggressive side of
myself like I I found myself at work
like standing up for myself a lot more I
found myself like being a lot more Stern
in my conversations like areas that I
hadn't realized that people were kind of
like walking over me and kind of like
mistaking my my kindness for weakness
sort of thing I started like calling
people on their not in like a
you it's not like I like became some
sort of mean Tyrant or anything but just
in the subtle way that only I could
notice um the the micro doing seemed to
like bring this thing to the Forefront
of my mind that I that I realized later
on that you know like it's okay to be
Stern it's okay to like feel anger
honestly like anger is okay like it
letting can't control you or like having
outbursts you know nobody wants that but
it's okay to like use this emotion of um
you know like sternness and and um you
know if I truly think that something is
right and I truly think something is
we're standing up for it's okay to you
know kind of like raise the tone of my
voice a little bit once in a while it
was was very interesting because like
that was not at all what I was thinking
I would get out of of micro doing you
know in any way and um so so it's very
interesting man I I I think uh I wonder
if so so you said when you were doing
that trip um there was like this this
feeling of being alone like when you
went into the basement and the lighting
was different and stuff do you think
that that the following months or the
following you know time afterwards did
that make you kind of look at your
relationship with with being alone in
some ways did that like become more
things to unwind for
you it it showed me the peace ful aspect
of it like I said the the possibilities
of becoming more peaceful on the
spiritual path but it also showed me
things that I needed to work on and one
of those things was feeling like I'm
alone and what that really means for me
and my relationship to to loneliness now
has changed quite a bit and I realized
that the kind of loneliness that I was
feeling during the trip um was feeling
like I couldn't um count on people to be
there for me and I realized that was
actually my own insecurity and not
really loneliness in that sense but more
so um feeling really separate from
people and having to understand what
that really means for me and yeah that
that trip was really interesting because
like I said it showed me like the two
sides of the coin and and how you know
this other side of it can really affect
you on your
Journey yeah yeah wow I mean it's such
an incredible thing I'm really excited
for the future of of like the
Psychedelic studies you know of course
helping people with PTSD and these sorts
of things but you know um something that
I probably said over and over on this
podcast too as Terence McKenna would say
like if the evolution of Consciousness
isn't the way out then I don't know what
is you know and and I think the more we
learn about ourselves and the more we
learn about our identities and the more
we're able to like take these experience
es that happen while we're um under the
influence of some sort of psychedelic
drug and and integrate them in a way
that helps us understand who and what we
are
um I think I think allows us to act from
that place of of who and what we really
are rather than our egoic you know like
I'm you know I'm this police officer and
so I have this you know power over
people and they do what I said you know
just like getting caught up in our our
roles and our identity which is so easy
for the the Western mind but there's a
lot of uh there's a lot of valuable
stuff like that can be gained from
just like being shown who you truly are
right like you just it's like so it's so
freeing you know and so I know I I um
thanks again for sharing that man I I
love I love to think of the future of
what psychedelics will bring our culture
and kind of um and also on another side
note like like I don't know if freaks me
out or if it excites me or both equally
but uh I've heard uh this guy Hamilton
Morris who is like very dipped into like
the Psychedelic Community he talks about
like with this new technology and new AI
stuff they're going to be able to start
synthesizing new psychedelics and like I
mean what do we do with that like I mean
I don't want to be the guine pig for
that but also in some parts it's like
how exciting you know but um I don't
know if if we could bring it in a way
that helps us understand ourselves in in
in the universe and our place in it and
um you know
also if if exploring these new
technologies with psychedelics can ease
suffering you know I mean let's let's do
it let's let's sail into the unknown you
know it's kind of
exciting yeah I mean not many people
know and I I don't even really know if I
would call it like a micro dose but it
was definitely not a full dose I
definitely knew that I didn't want to
take a full dose um this night I was
experimenting with the mushrooms um but
I thought I'm GNA take like a really
small micro do and and try and do a
chill step mix so the mix that I ended
up completing was it's on my SoundCloud
it's the only OSHA mix that I have right
now and I remember um before I even
started making the mix um I was really
contemplating um the ego and the
personality and my mind was just just
spinning circles on on the mushrooms and
just thinking about things and I
remember saying to myself like it
doesn't exist I don't exist and I
remember just my mind kind of being
blown apart during that and just
thinking wow like it's just just doesn't
exist you know and it just gives you
things to think about when you kind of
come off your trip and you've kind of
get your reality back of of you know you
can think about things that happened
during the trip kind of explore um what
that means to quote not exist um but I
remember making the oosha mix and I
heard you know his story and and his
kind of thing of like having all the
rolls-royces and and being this this
Guru that had a lot of scandals behind
it and and I remember just making the
mix and and listening to what he was
saying and I was like well it sounds
good so I'm just going to use use it and
just try and make this mix and when I
listen to the mix um when I'm not on a
psychedelic I realized that the mix is
actually quite simple it was quite um
not really complex or not really dense
and it was interesting because when I
was on psychedelic making the mix um I I
was like wow this is amazing like this
is good stuff you this is the answers to
the universe I found yeah right and I
remember just just vibing out to the
music and just thinking such an
incredible experience this is and I was
so excited to post that mix to YouTube
because I thought it was like the
greatest thing I ever made and I look
back now and it's it's a good mix but
it's it's definitely not in my top
three yeah yeah well okay so I'm I'm
gonna put I'm gonna put a hard question
to you um you know we we've mentioned a
couple times um I'm always kind of aware
of the listener that like doesn't really
know what the heck we're talking about
but it's kind of interesting what do you
mean when you say you don't
exist
um I would say to
that it can be a very complex answer I
think the purpose of the spiritual path
is to kind of understand that answer and
you can kind of explain it and I'm not
really the greatest with words but when
I do try and make sense of it and and
explain that to someone else I would
say that um your storyline of of who you
think you are like your childhood
experiences and the way you relate to to
reality itself and and kind of who you
believe yourself to be um doesn't
actually exist in the sense of like it's
not the absolute truth it's it's
relatively real but it's not
it's not what you would call reality in
the way that you think reality works and
so that's a really hard thing to grasp
and and a really hard thing to explain
to people and I think that when you have
a spiritual awakening you can kind of
understand what that means intuitively
and you can feel what that means rather
than um have some sort of specific
explanation for it and I think the more
you you learn about it the better you
can be at explaining it to other people
and so I'm still learning ways to
explain it better to people yeah yeah
know that's why that's why I
prefrontostriatal like you know uh like
I'm very sure about it you know and
they're like what are you talking about
cuz it's it's inevitably freaky you know
it's it's just something that it's I
mean basically in the first
place even questioning like a self or uh
like even just going to the point of you
don't realize it but you have a jump off
point like you have an identity that you
act from and you've probably never
really even thought about that fact
before and you know
there's a lot of stuff that you can
there's a lot of questions that you can
go through and there's a lot of videos
on YouTube and stuff that can kind of
unwind you know like so who are you um
are
you your arm no I'm not my arm I am my
arm but I'm not just my arm okay like
are you um you know who who is pumping
your organs right now is it you well no
I I mean I have organ they're inside my
body but you know you can like just kind
of unwind these things and realize that
you're just much more vast and um I
understand that that it I understand
sometimes when I explain it how I freak
people out and so I'm always like
backpedaling and and um um you know
because it's kind of this beautiful
freeing thing if you if you can kind of
really um not in intellectualize it not
really truly grasp it but there's kind
of this this feeling that it pokes in
and it's um it helps you kind of like
take off a little bit of like the really
tight clothing of of being a small
separate self who is who is suffering
you know rather than just like um the
experience of Consciousness in the
present moment so it's it's um it can
get really freaky I I I I feel drawn to
I was just listening to um have you
heard of Sam Harris Landon have you
heard of him um yeah I believe you
actually mentioned him to me before I
think that's where I heard that name
right right yeah yeah uh I sent you one
of his lectures he has this lecture
death in the present moment it's it's
one of my favorites it's um it's a
little dry it's a little like um it it
doesn't really have like a gentleness
that a lot of spiritual teachers have
because Sam is very
like um he's very scientific with with
this stuff so it comes across a little
cold and kind of like hardened in in
some senses but there's a lot of value
but um basically and hopefully I don't
butcher this too much but he talks about
the best metaphor for this like no no
self thing or like looking for the self
or um you know like a lot of meditations
are kind of like they'll have some sort
of cue Point um of you know you're in
this meditative State and it'll go okay
now look for the one who is looking you
know and that's like what what what are
you talking about you know and it's
supposed to kind of like do this about
face you find that there's nothing to
find and it's kind of gets you to this
peaceful open space of not looking for
who you are like you kind of just
instantly like in the just like you hit
a bell it has this reverberating
frequency after you hit the Bell it's
kind of that like you just rest in this
like there's nobody to find sort of
thing so Sam Harris has this poter of
look for the one who's looking um he
gives this metaphor that essentially
there was this um there was like a tour
bus in
Asia and uh there was all these people
on this bus and they made a stop at some
sort of like gift shop or something of
the like and everybody got off and they
had some time okay everybody meet back
at the bus in an hour and there was
people of different languages so there
was language barriers um you know
amongst all the participants on the bus
and one of the ladies who was by her
self she she changed her clothing so
like she went into the bathroom of this
gift shop whatever and changed her
clothing put her clothing in the bag um
and then it was you know an hour had
passed everybody was coming back on to
the bus and the lady who was sitting
next to the person um who had changed
was like wait hold on we're missing
somebody the lady that was that was
sitting next to me you know wearing a a
red shirt or whatever like I'm not
seeing her and so everybody again
there's language barrier so it couldn't
be like completely communicated and
everybody started looking for this woman
and then apparently it turns
into like a search like you know nearly
like call the helicopters like this lady
is missing and what happens is the lady
who had changed because the language
barrier a lot too she didn't realize
that she was there they were looking for
her but she had changed her clothes they
were looking for like a small Asian lady
who meets this description and she
didn't realize it this entire time so
she jumps in on the search she's looking
for herself and she doesn't even know it
and so they like the hours go by you
know it's deep into the night and then
um the way Sam Harris explains it is
like Suddenly at like 3:00 in the
morning through whatever like
conversations this lady suddenly
realizes oh we're looking for me I'm
helping I'm helping a search for me I
was never missing and so a lot of the
point with the looking for oneself is
that she was never missing there's no
self that can now be found like the way
to to call off the search isn't to find
the lady that was missing it's to
realize that she was never missing in
the first place and a lot of the um that
move in meditation of kind of like the
ADV vant Zen way of of uh like the
meditative looking for oneself you
realize there's nobody to find that
metaphor kind of paints it nicely
because it's not to complete this task
we must find this lady it's to realize
that she she was never missing in the
first place and so this nonself
of how do I find that there's no me to
see this like movement of looking back
upon oneself and saying that you were
never there isn't so much of a you know
a success that you cross a Finish Line
it's realizing like the it's almost a
flaw in the question itself um and and I
found that he I was just listening to a
podcast with Sam Harrison he repeated
that he's repeated a couple times but he
retold that story and so it's it's um
it's it's fresh of my mind but um I I
can see how that's that's confusing um
uh for many people who are like aren't
super familiar with it but it's also
this kind of fascinating story of going
ah like okay so there was never really a
there was never really a self to be
found in the first place um and and I
don't know if um if any of the people
that you listen to lecture-- wise if if
they if they have any of those sort of
of pointings to or anything stands out
to you um about kind of the the no self
stuff but I don't know man does does
that resonate with you like do you ever
have any of your experiences of kind of
being like freaked out by the no self
notion at all too I
wonder um yeah it was hard for me
to understand kind of what that meant um
it was felt like a very loaded question
I was like I don't I don't really know
how to answer that and I feel like what
helped me most actually a teacher that
helped me understand it um was Muji
because he um sort of did that peeling
back of asking the question like are you
your arm are you your body and you sort
of go through that process of of
answering those questions and then you
kind of come to this space where you're
like okay well then if I'm not the body
and if I'm not the mind then who am I
and it sort of opens you up to that
question in a way that you can
understand it because I remember
listening to um non-d dual teachers who
um were quite different than ramdas and
and ramdas definitely speaks from the
heart and he talks about very vulnerable
things and and that's initially why I
was drawn to him um but there was a
teacher um Rupert spir I think that's
how you say his name but he's a non-d
duel teacher and listening to to his
videos online at first were hard for me
to understand and contemplate and he
definitely said says things in a way
that I think can be difficult for anyone
to understand if they're new to that
information and the more you're around
it the more you start to to understand
it but I think Muji the way he teaches
his self- inquiry helps people um
understand or detach from the things
that they think they are and helps point
to to a deeper place and um the use of
the word like just pure awareness that
that help you understand it a little bit
more and kind of helps you put a name to
it um even though it's quite
formless in that way and the more I
listened to or the more I used muji's
process the more I started to understand
um teachers like rert and and sort of
the non-d Dual way of explaining things
and I think what's interesting
is sometimes that way of
explaining the
nonduality um I have found has led me
to
um spiritual bypass and it's very
interesting
because ramas definitely incorporates
the heart aspect of it and a lot of the
non- teachers that I see emerging in the
space and um teachers that are are not
well known right now but they're they're
kind of doing their own little side gig
and and coming to their own realizations
and and sharing those
realizations I found recently that um
this might not be true for everyone but
the way I perceived it really led me to
some kind of spiritual
bypassing um because it was this uh way
of clinging to a spiritual concept like
non-duality to take you out of your
emotions and your feelings and so I kind
of had to go through that um spiritual
bypassing phase and and recognize that
that's what I was doing and I wasn't
conscious of it so when I realized I was
doing it I kind of had like all these
recriminations towards myself of like
you know I can't believe you you
bypassed in this way and and the way you
can kind of share that with other people
and sort of um introduce them into
spiritual bypassing um I really had a
lot of Shame around that and so I had to
understand how that happened and and how
I got to that initial bypassing and how
nonduality um is perfectly explained but
definitely when you're perceiving it or
when you're um introducing yourself into
that information it's really great to
also include your heart into those
teachings as
well yeah brilliantly said man I love
That Could you um for someone who maybe
isn't familiar with the term spiritual
bypassing how do you describe
it um recently I like to look at
definitions online to to really
understand what it is because I was
trying to to decipher that uh when I was
seeing myself do it and I recognized
that for me it it felt like a clinging
to some kind of spiritual concept to
initially avoid or have aversion towards
emotions that you feel in the body and
to um I would describe it as a a pre
pre- transcendental State it's a feeling
of overcoming your emotions in some
sense but really what you're doing is is
avoiding them but it gives the illusion
um that you've kind of overcome the
emotions of The Human Experience and
you're more identified with your your
spiritual um identity in that sense yeah
yeah I I like that and I think what's
what's been fun for me is um like
noticing how often I have different
versions of spiritual bypassing come up
like it's not something like okay I
conquered spiritual bypassing I won't do
that again it's like you know there's
always some little other version that
sneaks its way in it's like a constant
unfolding it's like okay in which ways
am I doing that same thing again oh I'm
trying to like just insert that I don't
have a self who could ever feel that bad
emotion so it must not exist you know
like it's a it can really get kind of
like really get kind of messy you know
and and I think that um it's something
that like can really be explored and it
can really it's something that could
take its own shape and its own form
continuously too like I don't think
there's even just like trying to trying
to ask you to Define what spiritual
bypassing is is tough because it's like
a continuous kind of thing that we
always almost if if you're on some sort
of path or you're listening to any of
these sort of things you kind of have to
be keep you have to put yourself in
check almost you know you have to really
open open new doors and see what what
kind of comes at
you yeah i' I've recognized that the the
spiritual bypassing is is a part of the
path and to kind of push it away and and
hold some kind of Shame around it just
really ins Stills the the feedback loop
and it's been really useful to kind of
break that Loop when it starts to to
circle around and you start to have that
shame of like I can't believe I did this
and just sort of break in at that point
and just have that awareness that um you
were unconscious while you were doing it
and if you kind of knew you were doing
it you wouldn't do it right and you know
there's people like like Carl Young Who
there's a quote can't remember it and it
entirety but he says you can't chase
Shadows of light you have to integrate
Your Shadow cell and and really what's
happening is when you're when you're
bypassing there's kind of like a split
within you because one part of you feels
one way and the other part of you feels
completely different and you can't come
to that um place where you transcend
something if you're split in two
different ways and so yeah it's it's
really important to to integrate those
those parts of us that that feel one way
and to really embrace our emotions and
um hold the balance between um being on
a spiritual path and also having a human
experience yeah yeah very much so you I
feel like what how it showed up for me a
lot at the beginning was like this
overwhelming level of toxic positivity I
was like if it's not good vibes get it
away from me you know like in any point
um I actually use it as
at the end of one of my songs is a a
Romos quote um where he talks about like
how he he did all this work and he was
meditating and blah blah blah and he he
got all this shaki and T and then he
says but the problem was I wasn't free
you know like you can reject everything
that's negative or nasty and just not
look at it but that doesn't mean that
it's not there you know it's a it's
another it's another trick we play on
ourselves you know it's because part of
you're not just a spirit ual being you
know you're also a spiritual being
you're very human too and you're going
to get angry and you're going to have
you know you know you're going to get a
rash that itches that you got to itch
and you got to take out the garbage and
you got to you know there's all these
things about um you can't just reject
anybody that's coming about in in your
life I remember just more on my toxic
positivity I I had this friend group
message that like would had just been
you know just a friend group message you
know they're just sometimes it's memes
sometimes it's like you know just
talking sometimes it's just you
know just hanging out with your friends
in a group message sort of thing and I
remember when I first started going
through all this stuff like anybody that
would start sending anything that I
deemed to be not positive I would
respond back like hey I don't want to
hear it man I'm going through a lot
right now like keep that away from me
and I was like trying to control the way
that my like people that I loved my
friends I was trying to control the way
that they showed up and you know just
like you better keep that away from me
you're not going to be friends with me
and like I see now how how how
incredibly dorky that was of me and you
know what but also you know just like
you said very elegantly was um like
giving myself patience because I I felt
really guilty once I realized what I had
done I felt really like gross and like
ah man like why did I try to control my
friends and blah blah and that started
this you know shame spiral and you know
then you got to kind of give yourself
some Grace it's like man I didn't know I
thought that I was trying to do the
right thing at the moment I thought that
I thought that like the bad Vibe stuff
was actually what was harming me you
know when it was something that I just
need to like understand more about
myself and and integrate all of those
things you know it's not like you just
integrate Only the Good fluffy stuff you
know it's it's all of it it's the Human
Experience is is not just seeking
happiness it's it comes with depression
and sadness and heartbreak and and
negativity and and all of it you know
it's the whole thing that you that you
accept not just reject all the bad so it
can all be good
right yeah and I understand it in the
way that you know we see things like
non-duality and we listen to teachers
like that who have a a different way of
explaining things as opposed to someone
like ramdas and I kind of see that when
you have these experiences where there's
a lot of emotion in you and you your
responsibility is to integrate those
emotions but also recognize that you
can't come to these higher realizations
unless you intuitively feel it like
within your body almost um you can
understand things conceptually and you
can have a lot of knowledge but I don't
think that it really converts to wisdom
unless you have some kind of experience
or Awakening um which at times can be
quite an emotional thing and I think the
the way I was kind of bypassing it was
understanding it
intellectually um and then there were
other parts of of my body that weren't
really um in that place of understanding
because it hadn't integrated itself it
was only trying to reach those things
through the mind and not
intuitively I would love to explore a
little more on that I mean as someone
who listens to a lot of these spiritual
lectures um I think that you might have
a good input on this like the
the like the intellectualizing versus
the like just allowing it to kind of
work in your body sort of thing um like
the you know I think a lot of people if
if they listen to like a lot of the
spiritual lectures that that we enjoy um
I think a lot like especially in the
Western World we're kind of trained to
like listen so we have the information
so we can take the test later and get
the answers right and get a A plus on
our report card you know but like a lot
of this stuff is not I mean part of the
most most important thing while you're
listening is trying is rather not trying
to grab on to it the whole time not
trying to intellectualize it like
allowing your mind to think and and
explore and go oh what does that mean
and all that stuff but being okay with
the not knowing like being okay with
kind of your feet off the ground sort of
thing because a lot of those spiritual
lectures I mean for me anyway um and let
me know if it's like this for you it
feels like it's working through me if
I'm if I'm doing it right you know if
I'm if I'm it's it's trying it's me
getting out of my way intellectually
trying to not hold it and grab
everything that I'm hearing and trying
to like compare it with other things
I've heard and blah blah blah it's just
kind of like listening and almost just
having this internal head knot of like
ah okay I I hear that you know um I
wonder I wonder how you parse those two
things kind of like allowing it to work
through your body versus
intellectualizing it trying to grab on
to
it I think you said a very good point
about um kind of not having a place to
really put your feet on the ground and
just reminds me of ramdas not having a
place to stand and understanding that
you may not know all the different
complexities of it and just being open
to the mystery and and really having um
nowhere to stand um allows you to be on
different planes simultaneously and I
think think that intellectually when
you're kind of grabbing on to something
you're essentially putting your place um
putting yourself in a place to stand and
yeah I think really the purpose of it is
to to stand nowhere and to to be on
these planes simultaneously and and to
not be just in the spiritual plane and
to also you know have your your heart
and the The Human Experience which is
can be described as a different plane
than like the spiritual plane M yeah
yeah it's like it's all spiritual you
know it's not this whole this whole
separate thing you know it's not this
it's and it's also not trying to take
everything we hear and only fit it into
spirituality you know it's it's like how
to it's very much we're very much having
a human experience and and part of that
is you know discovering our spiritual
nature and those sorts of things but
it's also all the icky stuff that comes
with being a human too and and getting
mad and getting upset and having
heartbreak break and you know farting
and and all of it you know like it's all
it's all it's all you know right for the
taking you
know yeah the way I kind of um remind
myself is it's the emotions and stuff
that's not any less spiritual it's it's
it's all part of the dance it's all it's
all spiritual and it's when you begin to
separate it and see it as something
that's that's separate from your kind of
spiritual understanding of something you
begin to kind of push it away from
yourself and it's when you see it as
spiritual you embrace the emotions and
pull them in
closer yeah nicely said um I wonder what
you think about like the modern
spiritual lecture that's on YouTube and
the like the guru nature so we'
mentioned rhas you know tons of times a
favorite of both of ours certainly um
and and he followed you know what's
known as the p of the guru he found like
a you know an actual like physical man
who um who he like followed and he
devoted himself too and like you know
every word that his Guru said um you
know was was like everything to ramdas
and and this whole path of the guru um I
wonder like the modern Guru sometimes I
wonder if it's
like like literally YouTube lectures
like I mean I have so many teachers I
have so many teachers like I couldn't
just pick one I mean there's I certainly
have favorites you know I certainly have
like certain people on online that I
love listening to like you know many of
them you include in in in your chill
step mixes um but I wonder
like like if the path of you know
spiritual enlightenment or the path of
the guru kind of does change in like
have its own evolution of like cuz man
think about how many how many dudes just
like you and me get profound like
spiritual you know advancement or or
like you know steps towards
Enlightenment for for lack of way way
better words there um just from like
YouTube lectures like like do you wonder
about like the the path of the guru kind
of becoming its its own kind of new
thing in in in a
sense it's really interesting because I
remember um ramas talking about his
relationship to maharaji and
when he left his body um he was still
kind of in his experiences through his
day-to-day life and so anytime something
would come up you know he would think oh
it's just my Guru you know just sort of
messing with me and and having that uh
relationship um has helped me in my
connection to ramdas because I didn't
know you know maharaji personally so
there isn't quite the same pull that
there is to to ramdas and
you know now that he's left his body um
even when he was still alive I think I
kind of created that same relationship
to ramdas where if something was
happening and I was caught in my
day-to-day experiences I would just
think of ramdas and think of his voice
and and what he would say to me in that
moment and so in that sense um I would
say he kind of became my own little Guru
and then like with teachers online um
there's so many teachers that I also
look up to and and think about their
teachings and in my day-to-day life and
kind of hear their voice as well so yeah
I think that they all have this um
potential to to be gurus to me in in any
moment and I think um what I've been
recognizing is some of the people that I
my mind kind of puts up on a pedestal I
come back to to that saying um God Guru
and self are one and the same and I
recognize that these people are a direct
reflection of that own um innate Essence
that exists within me and so whatever
knowledge I'm picking up on from someone
else is just something that I already
know and something I already am and so I
I've kind of break that separation of
like um putting that person up on a
pedestal and kind of woring worshiping
them in that sense and and see it as
worshiping
myself yeah yeah yeah because it's um it
really is in in I mean many people say
it certainly romed us it really is like
a remembering rather than someone
parsing entirely new knowledge to us and
then we like make our own decisions from
there like when you allow like the
spiritual lectures or these things that
they're pointing at to work through you
there is some sort of uh like you fall
back into it where rather than lean
forward and do the work and and arrive
there you know it is this remembering is
is really I think the best word when
when you're allowing the spiritual
lectures to kind of work through you is
it's reminding you who you are not
teaching you who you are in a sense
like I it it it really is I'm drawn to
ramdas has this thing where he talks
about this uh this lady who was sitting
in the front row this this older lady
and uh he was giving his lecture and um
he was he was just talking about the
whole time this older lady she's just
nodding her head like oh yeah yeah
that's it like you know I get it oh yeah
you're saying it right that sort of
stuff and then afterwards he talks to
her and uh and he was curious he's he's
like how do you like how do you know you
know like what do you do what do you
practice and she leans into him and
she's like I
knit and it's just this like oh it's
just so wonderful you know like
it's this thing that we already know
like however you get there is okay but
there's
something about you know the Divine you
what you think you are that's like that
can't be taken away it can't you know
even if language itself was was erased
like it's still there you know and so a
lot of what these you know teachers or
gurus or whatever are trying to share is
is um you know this thing that you've
always been that you couldn't possibly
not be and so it's just reminding you
what you are not and it comes with it a
remembering of of all that you
are yeah um the the non-duality teachers
uh kind of helped me come to this
realization like in the western religion
the tendency is to to place God outside
yourself and to to worship this thing
that is separate from you and I think
even on the spiritual path like
listening to rhas talk about his
relationship to God and and when you
listen to that you can kind of still
have that separation feeling in you of
like this is God is something outside of
me and I really came to recognize the
ways in which I was doing that um to
myself and how I was placing this kind
of idea outside of myself and the
nonduality teachings helped we recognize
that that um God that we speak of is the
self and the true self
and it really just opened me up in a new
way because I stopped um identifying
with my smallness and recognized um the
vast expansiveness of of who I really am
and what that really
means yeah yeah absolutely it's a I I I
feel uh so I have this and I got it
years ago I have on on my wrist one of
my tattoos is only I can judge me and uh
years ago is before I had any sort of
spiritual background um and it it was
kind of like this jokey I'm sure you've
heard the the Tupac term Only God can
judge me and I wasn't like religious or
spiritual or had any I had I had no
place for those words to sit in in my
life um I didn't grow up with any of
that sort of background none of it was
anything to me until I was like 26
actually but uh it's so funny because I
walk around with this you know it's look
at me right in the eye all the time it's
right on my right wrist you know and
it's funny because the meaning of the
tattoo has has drastically changed to me
you know like this the eye on it is this
very big Capital Eye and so now I see it
not as this like small like oh you can't
judge me I'm an individual you know like
I'm so cool is what I was probably
thinking when I got the tattoo but now
it's like only I capital I can judge me
and so as much as I was trying to be
cool and get rid of the Only God can
judge me it's like even more prevalent
like the the god that is that is within
me is you know right here on my
wrist yeah it's funny you say that I
have like a similar tattoo story um at
the time when I was like really young
going through my teenage years I related
a lot to metal music and what you would
call sco and it helped me um kind of get
to know my own emotional pain through
that kind of music and there was a band
um they did a lot of music where it was
like spoken word poetry I don't know if
you're familiar they're called law
dispute
and at the time I thought to myself that
for my first tattoo I was going to get a
law dispute tattoo and I was going to
get some lyrics um to put on it's
basically just like a flower on my
forearm with a quote which is a lyric
and it says we are not our failures and
at the time I just thought you know it
was just a cool tattoo you know whatever
and then the more I look at like the
quote itself we are not our failures I
often look at that tattoo and I'm
spiling through you know my own kind of
Shame and whatnot and and recognizing
that I am not in fact my failures and my
mistakes and so it's it's become a good
reminder for
me yeah yeah it's so cool how you know a
perception can change so drastically but
still really hold a lot of a lot of
juice still hold a lot of like really
really good stuff you know it as we
transform you know is as much as like
you know people without tattoos would
say like oh you're going to have that
forever like are you sure you want to
have that forever and um it's as much as
it's like you know it's it's a
reflection of who we were at the time
there's also a relationship with our
with our art on our body that is well
what does it mean to me now you know and
we can continually ask oursel that and
and uh you know for me with any of my
tattoos I would never I would never say
like oh I don't like that anymore and
I'm embarrassed of that like I've always
kind of scratched my head when people
are like they regret their tattoos it's
like man that's that's truly who you
were at that time and your reflection
when you look at it now shouldn't be
shame or or regret or any of those sorts
of things it's like a it's a reminder of
how far you've come if like if you don't
if you're not into that thing anymore or
it doesn't speak to you in the same way
like that's awesome actually you know
it's nothing to be to be bummed about or
like try to put yourself down for who
you were when you were younger it's a
it's a you know it's it's all memories
of of of who you once were it's all it's
all cave paintings of of your Evolution
you know it's it's a cool
thing yeah yeah it definitely like like
you said it just reminds you of of the
past version of you that you really
identified with and you you see the ways
you identified with this this storyline
you had of yourself and it's just
interesting to look at now the ways in
which you perceived yourself then versus
the way you see yourself
today yeah and then like finding space
to to give yourself grace through it and
and like you know to recognize man I was
I was pretty mean to myself I was tough
on myself I was blah blah blah but I'm
not anymore and that's pretty cool you
know like just I love it I think it's a
it's magical thing you know I mean is
you know maybe if I had like a swastika
on my forehead maybe I might be saying
something different but you know I think
uh we we all grow and we all like become
new versions of ourselves and and that
comes with who we once were and and it's
accepting that you know it's kind of
like the you know the the inner child
work you know you don't you would never
speak meanly to like if there was a a
six-year-old version of yourself
standing next to you you wouldn't be so
rude and disrespectful and insult him
and put him down you you know if if he
was standing right next to you you would
be kind and you would be understanding
of of why he thinks the way he does at
that time and you see that now you have
these different experiences and so you
you bring love to who you once were you
don't it's it's I have this line the ego
the ego doesn't like change nor grit but
loves to feel withhold you know it's
it's not about trying to destroy the ego
it's not about trying to destroy who you
once were it's it's how can you love
them for exactly who they were from who
you are now you know it's it's a
constant practice um brother we are we
are getting up here in time I I don't
want to keep you too much too much
longer but um I'd love to kind of as as
we round the the final lap here
um what what is what what is the future
of your Chillstep mixes and and where do
you see yourself heading um you know
what what direction are you heading with
with your spiritual work in in the you
know you're very much an artist and I
wonder kind of like where you see
yourself are you going to continue to
share these sorts of things are you
going to keep making mixes um I hope
it's a yes and I hope yes you'll say yes
that um you'll continue to like share
your your awesome pictures and like your
life and your perspective on your social
media and stuff too are you planning on
continue going forward with this
stuff yeah um for a while I kind of like
really stepped away from the mixes and
wasn't sure if I was if it was something
I was going to continue to do and I
recognize now the impact of them and and
how far they've gone and I think some of
the ones I I've made I don't think I
could ever like recreate even different
versions of those mixes because the way
they came about was just so natural and
so organic and some of the ones I have
are probably the best ones I'll ever do
in my opinion but I do find myself
thinking about them more recently of
like how can I give outside of my other
Artistry like through my pictures and
and perspectives I share online and I
find that the Chillstep mixes were and
still are um a gift of mine that I can
still give and so when I inally feel
drawn to do a mix um there will be times
where I'll sit down and and try and
create one and and recently I've tried
to to do a new one and I've just been
finding myself sitting down and it's
just not coming through the way it used
to and so I kind of just give myself
space for that and to just maybe come
back to it in the future um I don't take
it as like I can't do this anymore you
know maybe now it's just not the right
time for it but I definitely still think
about it and and still want to um
produce more I think there's other
teachers I haven't even touched and and
I could use their lectures as well and
I've had great suggestions from people
on on mixes to do next I think really
what I'm tuning into now is sharing my
own perspectives online and I really
feel drawn to that path um for some
reason I just feel like it's something I
need to explore um how to share myself
and move kind of through my own
insecurities about myself and public
speaking and sort of understand the
stories and the identification I have
around that and and how that's um
anchoring me into my own limiting
beliefs still so I would say I'm kind of
just following my heart right now and
kind of just experimenting with the
things that are are really enticing me
to to move forward with so yeah I love
that I think that's a fantastic answer
you know because it's h it's got to it
can't be forced you know it has to be
along the lines of when you sit down to
create some art or share something it
has to kind of has to flow out of you
rather than like trying to you know like
squeeze a lemon as hard as you can and
try to get all the juice out of it you
know so yeah I hope you do the same and
I'll say just as a you know a fellow
artist friend over here I very much in
in the same boat you know there's so
many times that I put a lot of pressure
on myself um or try to like I get
momentum or I get like I notice that you
know I'm getting a big uptick in
listener to the podcast or like checking
out my art or whatever I'm like oh
should I like I really like attack this
should I like try to continue so I can
get more people to listen and help more
people and blah you know it becomes
about myself so quickly but um I think
that the best way for me has been to
just not put so much pressure pressure
on myself remember that nobody's grading
it that I don't have a boss breathing
down my neck you know my art is my art
and I get to share it you know um from
my perspective of of how I'm actually
feeling at that time in in my life so
you know it's it took me I just got a
reminder this I've I've been doing this
podcast for four years actually it seems
crazy but um and and I just just now got
past 100 episodes you know so that's
it's a lot of episodes but four years is
quite a long time you know so I I try
not not to I try not to get too obsessed
about timelines or deadlines or any of
that sort of stuff um and I just kind of
Express how I'm feeling and if I have
nothing to say and I can't squeeze
anything out then I try to give myself
Grace and just cool then I guess I got
nothing to say right now you know so
yeah man I I resonate with that a lot
yeah I think that's when the best
content comes I think there's so much
energetics that go into to forcing it
and choosing to show up when you don't
really want to be there I mean sometimes
you know depending on your commitments
you have to show up but I think people
really recognize the the energy behind
it and if it feels like something that
comes from your own pure joy and Bliss
people really um pick up on that they
might not be conscious of it but it
might just be in the energy in the way
it's being received that you know your
content when you show up and you're
really excited about it people can
really feel that in some way yeah
absolutely I agree man I agree um well
so so what I would love to do um as as
we wrap up here is uh you know I'll tell
people to check down in the description
below um to find out find out more about
Mr dirty Zen over here um and I would
love to ask you and you could send me
the link afterwards of maybe like if you
had to choose your your favorite
Chillstep mix and I would love to
include that as the link below so if
this is your first time hearing about
Landon and you want to check out his
mixes um click on that one I had him
send me his favorite um otherwise um
it's it's dirty Zen on Instagram is
there anywhere else that you're posting
is there anywhere else we can find you
in any other resources to to throw in
before we wrap up here um mostly just
Instagram and my YouTube channel which I
show up to um pretty infrequently but
I'm trying to be a little bit more
committed with that um something that I
really want to do so um those are like
my two two major platforms Instagram and
YouTube yeah yeah yeah I love the work
you do and and again uh like YouTube is
definitely a cool place to go too cuz
you you visually you have such an eye
for videography and photography and uh
it's it's not only aesthetically
pleasing but it's you know it's it's
good spiritual knowledge for us too so
man thank you so much for your time
again man I I really appreciate this
thank you for being so like open and
willing and sharing your personal
stories and you know even right off the
bat when I first messaged you you were
like you know you address like hey you
know maybe I have some sort of anxieties
and a little reluctance but yeah I would
like to do that and so I I appreciate
your bravery as well man thank you so
much this isn't this isn't an easy thing
to do you know it's a we get in our
heads a lot with it you know speaking
for myself for sure so uh I'm I'm really
grateful for your time man thank you so
much yeah it's a it's a pleasure to be
here thank you for having me I really
enjoyed it cool all right well listeners
love yourselves take care of yourselves
if you drank no water today you're crazy
drink some water stretch check out
Landon stuff and uh we'll see you next
episode the junkyard love podcast
[Music]
at what age do we learn how to have
better
conversations at what age do we learn to
have better conversations with
[Music]
ourselves
knowledge is
[Music]
power reality
is